<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">ChildFieldTrip</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_animal_title">AnimalTitle</string>
    <string name="title_activity_domestic">Domestic</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dog">Dog</string>
    <string name="title_activity_farm_animals">FarmAnimals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cat">Cat</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rodents">Rodents</string>
    <string name="title_activity_reptiles">Reptiles</string>
    <string name="title_activity_birds">Birds</string>
    <string name="title_activity_horse">Horse</string>

    <string-array name="def">
        <item>Amphibian</item>
        <item>Canines</item>
        <item>Carnivore</item>
        <item>Feline</item>
        <item>Herbivore</item>
        <item>Nocturnal</item>
        <item>Mammal</item>
        <item>Omnivore</item>
        <item>Reptile</item>
        <item>Rodent</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="farm">
        <item>Cow</item>
        <item>Horse</item>
        <item>Pig</item>
        <item>Sheep</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="amp">
        <item>Frog</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="freshlv">
        <item>Salmon</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="sealv">
        <item>Dolphin</item>
        <item>Octopus</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rep">
        <item>Corn Snake</item>
        <item>Turtle</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rod">
        <item>Guinea Pig</item>
        <item>Ferret</item>
        <item>Hamster</item>
        <item>Mouse</item>
        <item>Rabbit</item>
        <item>Rat</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="bird">
        <item>Parakeet</item>
        <item>Parrot</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildmamals">
        <item>Baboon</item>
        <item>Bear</item>
        <item>Boar</item>
        <item>Buffalo</item>
        <item>Deer</item>
        <item>Elephant</item>
        <item>Gazelle</item>
        <item>Giraffe</item>
        <item>Gorilla</item>
        <item>Hippo</item>
        <item>Monkey</item>
        <item>Skunk</item>
        <item>Zebra</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildfelines">
        <item>Cheetah</item>
        <item>Leopard</item>
        <item>Lion</item>
        <item>Ocelot</item>
        <item>Panther</item>
        <item>Tiger</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildrodents">
        <item>Capybara</item>
        <item>Groundhog</item>
        <item>Meerkat</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildreptiles">
        <item>Alligator</item>
        <item>Chameleon</item>
        <item>Crocodile</item>
        <item>Iguana</item>
        <item>Lizard</item>
        <item>Rattlesnake</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildbirds">
        <item>Duck</item>
        <item>Eagle</item>
        <item>Penguin</item>
        <item>Seagull</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildcanines">
        <item>Coyote</item>
        <item>Fox</item>
        <item>Hyena</item>
        <item>Wolf</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="pig">Pig</string>
    <string name="guineapig">Guinea Pig</string>
    <string name="hamster">Hamster</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cow">Cow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_parrot">Parrot</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rabbit">Rabbit</string>
    <string name="title_activity_turtle">Turtle</string>
    <string name="title_activity_camera">CameraActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mouse">Mouse</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rat">Rat</string>
    <string name="title_activity_parakeet">Parakeet</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sheep">Sheep</string>
    <string name="title_activity_corn_snake">CornSnake</string>
    <string name="go">Go</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to the Animal Field Guide!</string>
    <string name="animals">Animals</string>
    <string name="spellgame">Spell Game</string>
    <string name="wiki">Images and information taken from Wikipedia</string>
    <string name="exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="image">Image here</string>
    <string name="horse">Horse</string>
    <string name="dog">Dog</string>
    <string name="cat">Cat</string>
    <string name="mouse">Mouse</string>
    <string name="rat">Rat</string>
    <string name="rabbit">Rabbit</string>
    <string name="turtle">Turtle</string>
    <string name="cornsnake">Corn Snake</string>
    <string name="cow">Cow</string>
    <string name="sheep">Sheep</string>
    <string name="parakeet">Parakeet</string>
    <string name="parrot">Parrot</string>
    <string name="choose">Click to choose!</string>
    <string name="reptiles">Reptiles</string>
    <string name="rodents">Rodents</string>
    <string name="birds">Birds</string>
    <string name="canines">Canines</string>
    <string name="felines">Felines</string>
    <string name="farmanimals">Farm Animals</string>
    <string name="defaullt">Here we put the description for the dog. Like what the dog eats. Where the dog lives. What is interesting about the dog. Whatever else</string>
    <string name="search">Search for an animal</string>
    <string name="domestic">Domestic</string>
    <string name="aquatic">Aquatic</string>
    <string name="wild">Wild Animals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_tiger">Tiger</string>
    <string name="tiger">Tiger</string>
    <string name="tiger_desc">Tigers are the biggest cat species. They can weigh up to almost 400 kg. They have orange bodies with dark stripes. They mostly feed on ungulates such as bovids. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_cheetah">Cheetah</string>
    <string name="cheetah">Cheetah</string>
    <string name="cheetah_desc">Cheetahs are found in Africa and the Middle East. They are the fasted land animal and run up to 120 km an hour. They are carnivores and eat mmals that are 40 kg and under. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_lion">Lion</string>
    <string name="lion">Lion</string>
    <string name="lion_desc">Lions are the second largest cat. The male lion has a mane used for confrontations with other lions for intimidation. Female lions hunt together in groups.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_zebra">Zebra</string>
    <string name="zebra">Zebra</string>
    <string name="zebra_desc">Zebras belong to the horse family. Each zebra has a unique pattern of stripes. They are social animals and live in herds.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_deer">Deer</string>
    <string name="deer">Deer</string>
    <string name="deer_desc">Deer (singular and plural) are the ruminant mammals that comprise the family Cervidae. Species therein include white-tailed deer, such mule deer as black-tailed deer, elk, moose, red deer, reindeer fallow deer, roe deer, pudú and chital.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_giraffe">Giraffe</string>
    <string name="giraffe">Giraffe</string>
    <string name="giraffe_desc">The giraffe is the tallest terrestrial animal. They live in South Africa. They feed on trees and bushes and eat in open areas to detect predators.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bear">Bear</string>
    <string name="bear">Bear</string>
    <string name="bear_desc">Bears are mammals with bulky bodies and short legs. They are diurnal animals, meaning the are active during the day. They are very asocial and are omnivores.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gazelle">Gazelle</string>
    <string name="gazelle">Gazelle</string>
    <string name="gazelle_desc">A gazelle is a species of antelope. They are fast animals, able to run 60 miles per hour. They are small and stand around three feet. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_elephant">Elephant</string>
    <string name="elephant">Elephant</string>
    <string name="elephant_desc">Elephants are the largest land animal. They can weigh up to 15,000 lbs. They are herbivorous and are capable of hearing low frequencies.  Females live in groups where one will be the leader, having her daughter take over the role when she is done.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hippo">Hippo</string>
    <string name="hippo">Hippo</string>
    <string name="hippo_desc">The name hippo means "river horse" in ancient Greek. They are the third largest mmamal that lives on land.They are relatives of whales. They spend most of their lives in the water.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_animals">WildAnimals</string>
    <string name="mammalso">Other Mammals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_other_mammals">OtherMammals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_canines">Canines</string>
    <string name="title_activity_felines">Felines</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_rodents">WildRodents</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_reptiles">WildReptiles</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_birds">WildBirds</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hamster">Hamster</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pig">Pig</string>
    <string name="title_activity_guineapig">Guineapig</string>
    <string name="title_activity_alligator">Alligator</string>
    <string name="alligator">Alligator</string>
    <string name="alligator_desc">Alligators have been alive for 37 million years. The adult weighs 360 kg. They live in freshwater such as swamps. In some situations, alligators will eat panthers and bears.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_meerkat">Meerkat</string>
    <string name="meerkat">Meerkat</string>
    <string name="meerkat_desc">Meerkats live in clans that normally contain 20 other meerkats. They live underground in burrows that have many entrances. A few meerkats will stand watch while other meerkats play and forage for food.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_penguin">Penguin</string>
    <string name="penguin">Penguin</string>
    <string name="penguin_desc">Penguins are flightless birds that live in Antartica. Their wings are flippers they use to swim in water.  They feed on fish, squid, and other sealife.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wolf">Wolf</string>
    <string name="wolf">Wolf</string>
    <string name="wolf_desc">Wolves live in units that are called packs or mated pairs. They are normally accompanied by their offspring. They are very territorial animals and establish territory to make claim on prey. They are monogamous, meaning they choose a mate for life.</string>
    <string name="deerinfo">Deer is both singular and plural way to refer to deers. They are also mammals and come from the Cervidae family. The males have antlers. They live in tundras to tropical forests. They are also herbivores.</string>
    <string name="facts">Facts</string>
    <string name="definitions">Definitions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_database_manager">DatabaseManager</string>
    <string name="catinfo">Cats are carniorous mammals. They are kept as indoor pets. They are valued by people for hunting vermin and being companions. They have quick reflexes, sharp claws, and are flexible.</string>
    <string name="cornsnakeinfo">Corn snakes are a popular breed of snake to keep as pets. They are carnivorous and eat  small rodents. Sometimes they may even eat smaller reptiles or unguarded bird eggs in the wild. They are found in the southeastern and central United States. </string>
    <string name="cowinfo">Cow are also called cattle. They are raised to be dairy animals for milk, or livestock for meat,. They were domesticated from southeast Turkey and there are about 1.3 billion of them in the world today.</string>
    <string name="doginfo">They are mammals part of the Canidae family and are subspecies of gray wolves. They were the first animal to be domesticated. They arenow used mostly as pets but were formally mostly domesticated for safety.</string>
    <string name="guineainfo">They are not in the pig family, but are actually rodents. They came from Andes. These animals are pets that were introduced by European traders to WEstern societies.  They eat vegitation. </string>
    <string name="hamsterinfo">Hamsters are mostly active during the night so they can avoid predators. Their diets may consist of seeds, vegetation, fruits and sometimes even insects. Their cheek pouches reach their shoulders so they can carry food to their homes. </string>
    <string name="horseinfo"> Horses are mammals that have evolved from around 50 million ears from being small multi-toed creatures into what they are today. They are used in many human activities such as police work, sports, agriculture, and riding. They are herbivores. </string>
    <string name="mouseinfo">Mice are small mammals. They are largely herbivores that eat grains. They are nocturnal animals. As well as being popular pets they are used as test subjects in labatories.</string>
    <string name="parakeetinfo">They are a subspecies of parrot. The ringnecked parakeet is the type native to Africa and Asia. This species is popular as a pet. </string>
    <string name="parrotinfo">Parrots are found in tropical and subtropical regions. They are divided into three superfamilies: true parrots, New Zealand parrots, and cockatoos.  South America and Australasia have the greatest diversity of parrots. Their diets consists of seeds, fruit, nuts, buds, and other parts of plants. A few eat animals.</string>
    <string name="piginfo">Pigs ancestors are the common Eurasian wild boar. Baby pigs are called piglets. They are omnivores and like to be social.  They are commonly raised on farms for pork, ham, and even leather. </string>
    <string name="rabbitinfo">Rabbits are mammals and found in many places over the world. A male rabbit is reffered to as a buck while the female as a doe. However a baby rabbit is called a kitten.  They live in meadows, woods, deserts, and grasslands. They are most active dawn and dusk and are herbivores. </string>
    <string name="ratinfo">Rats are often considered pests. However they have an ability to learn and are often kept as pets. They are often used in labatories.</string>
    <string name="sheepinfo">They are licestock mammals. They likely descended from mouflon in Europe and Asia. They are raised for meat, milk, and fleece. Their wool is the most used animal fiber.</string>
    <string name="turtleinfo">Turtles have a bony(cartilaginous) shell that is formed from their ribs. This shell acts like a protective shell. They are amniotes, which means they breathe air, and do not go underwater to lay eggs, but live around water.  They feed on aquatic plants and sometimes insects. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_spell_game">SpellGame</string>
    <string name="title_activity_image_guess">ImageGuess</string>
    <string name="title_activity_guess_image">GuessImage</string>
    <string name="title_activity_frog">Frog</string>
    <string name="frog">Frog</string>
    <string name="froginfo">Frogs are short-bodied and tailless. They evolve from a stage called tadpole. When they are tadpoles they are mostly herbivors but once they evolve they are carnivores. They used their cleft tongue to catch flies.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_aquatic">Aquatic</string>
    <string name="fresh">Fresh Water</string>
    <string name="amphibian">Amphibian</string>
    <string name="sea">Sea Water</string>
    <string name="title_activity_amphibian">Amphibian</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fresh_water">FreshWater</string>
    <string name="title_activity_salmon">Salmon</string>
    <string name="salmon">Salmon</string>
    <string name="dolphin">Dolphin</string>
    <string name="salmoninfo">Salmon are born  anadromous, which means they are born in the water. They then migrate to the ocean and only return  to fresh water to reproduce.  </string>
    <string name="title_activity_sea_water">SeaWater</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dolphin">Dolphin</string>
    <string name="dolphininfo">Dolphins are mammals that are closely related to whales. They eat squid and fish. They are thought of as most intelligent animal and are highly social.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_octopus">Octopus</string>
    <string name="octopus">Octopus</string>
    <string name="octopusinfo">Octupus have eight arms. Their mouthes have a hard beak and are located in the center of their arms. To defend themselves they will spray ink at their predators.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_monkey">Monkey</string>
    <string name="monkey">Monkey</string>
    <string name="monkey_desc">Monkeys are mid-size primates. They are found in South America and Central America. Their diets consist of fruits, insects, small mammals, and flowers.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gorilla">Gorilla</string>
    <string name="gorilla">Gorilla</string>
    <string name="gorilla_desc">Gorillas are large primates. They are mostly herbivorous and live in central Africa. They are close relatives to humans, only chimapnzees being closer.  </string>
    <string name="title_activity_baboon">Baboon</string>
    <string name="baboon">Baboon</string>
    <string name="baboon_desc">Baboons live on the ground and live in Savannahs. They are omnivorous, eating insects, hares, and even small antelopes. Baboons in captivity have lived up to 45 years. They live in groups up to 250 animals.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_buffalo">Buffalo</string>
    <string name="buffalo">Buffalo</string>
    <string name="buffalo_desc">Water buffalo will feed on aquatic plants during floods. They enjoy being in the water. They are great for tilling rice fields and have milk with more protein than a dairy cow.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_boar">Boar</string>
    <string name="boar">Boar</string>
    <string name="boar_desc">Boars are a species of pig. Female and babies live in groups while males are solitary. They forage for forr late at night or early in the morning, having an omnivores diet. They will fight if backed up into a corner and threatened.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fox">Fox</string>
    <string name="fox">Fox</string>
    <string name="fox_desc">Foxes are omnivores. The most common kind of fox is the red fox. There are foxes on almost every continent.  Foxes are wary of people and only the silver fox has been domesticated.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hyena">Hyena</string>
    <string name="hyena">Hyena</string>
    <string name="hyena_desc">Hyna make many vocal sounds such as grunts, giggles, whoops, and laughing. The spotted hyena is more dominant than the male hyena. They are carnivors who  phylogenetically are like felines, though their behavior is more line a canine.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_coyote">Coyote</string>
    <string name="coyote">Coyote</string>
    <string name="coyote_desc">Coyotes hunt for their food in pairs and live in large groups. They are the most abundant predators to attack livestock in America. They like to life in ubrrows made by groudhogs.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_leopard">Leopard</string>
    <string name="leopard">Leopard</string>
    <string name="leopard_desc"> Leopard is the smallest of the big cats. They can carry carcasses up big trees they climb. It will eat any animal it can hunt and is known for its stealth.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_panther">Panther</string>
    <string name="panther">Panther</string>
    <string name="panther_desc">They live in tropical rainforests. Black panthers still have markings of a leopard if looked at closely. This is known as ghost striping. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_ocelot">Ocelot</string>
    <string name="ocelot">Ocelot</string>
    <string name="ocelot_desc">Ocelots are also called dwarf leopards. They very much look like the domestic cat.In the night they are at their most active. If their territory is threatened it will fight for it, even to the death. They only meet their own kind when looking to mate.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_capybara">Capybara</string>
    <string name="capybara">Capybara</string>
    <string name="capybara_desc">Capybaras are the largest rodents of the world and live in South America. They are close relatives to guinea pigs. They are semi-aquatic and are herbivores. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_groundhog">Groundhog</string>
    <string name="groundhog">Groundhog</string>
    <string name="groundhog_desc"> Groundhogs are also called woodchucks. They weigh up to 4 kg. They are good at digging and have short limbs and thick claws. Their diet consists of wild vegetation, berries, and grasses.</string>
    <string name="back">Go Back</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="animal">Animals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ferret">Ferret</string>
    <string name="ferretinfo">A ferret is a small mammal from the weasel family. They are domesticated pets that are also used for hunting rabbits. They have long slength bodies averaging in 20 inches in length. They sleep up to 18 hours a day and are most active at night.</string>
    <string name="ferret">Ferret</string>
    <string name="title_activity_skunk">Skunk</string>
    <string name="title_activity_definitions">Definitions</string>
    <string name="skunk">Skunk</string>
    <string name="skunkinfo">Skunks spray a strong smelling liquid. They are omnivores and have very poor eyesight. When they are not breeding they are very solitary. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_rattlesnamke">Rattlesnamke</string>
    <string name="rattlesnake">Rattlesnake</string>
    <string name="rattlesnake_desc">Rattlesnakes are very venomous and dangerous snakes in the world. They care mainly found in the Americas ranging from Canada to Central Argentina.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_crocodile">Crocodile</string>
    <string name="crocodile">Crocodile</string>
    <string name="crocodile_desc">Crocodiles are equatic reptiles. They are largely found in Asia, the Americas, Africa, and Australia.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_chameleon">Chameleon</string>
    <string name="chameleon">Chameleon</string>
    <string name="chameleon_desc">Chameleons are part of lizard family. Their species varies with their colors and there are 160 species in total. Some Chameleons have the ability to change their colors. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_iguana">Iguana</string>
    <string name="iguana">Iguana</string>
    <string name="iguana_desc">Iguana is an herbivorous lizards. They are mainly found Central America, Mexico, Caribbean, Fiji and Tonga islands. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_lizard">Lizard</string>
    <string name="lizard">Lizard</string>
    <string name="lizard_desc">Lizards are squamate reptiles. They can be found in every part of the world except Antartica. Lizards normally have external ears and feet.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_duck">Duck</string>
    <string name="duck">Duck</string>
    <string name="duck_desc">Duck is the common name for a large number of species in the Anatidae family of birds, which also includes swans and geese. The ducks are divided among several subfamilies in the Anatidae family.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_eagle">Eagle</string>
    <string name="eagle">Eagle</string>
    <string name="eagle_desc">Eagle is a common name for some members of the bird family Accipitridae; it belongs to several genera that are not necessarily closely related to each other.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_seagull">Seagull</string>
    <string name="seagull">Seagull</string>
    <string name="seagull_desc">Seagulls are typically medium to large birds, usually grey or white, often with black markings on the head or wings. They typically have harsh wailing or squawking calls, stout, longish bills, and webbed feet.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_chicken">Chicken</string>
    <string name="chicken">Chicken</string>
    <string name="chicken_desc">The chicken is the most common and widespread domesticated fowl. Their population in 2003 was believed to be over 24 billion in the world.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_goldfish">Goldfish</string>
    <string name="goldfish">Goldfish</string>
    <string name="goldfish_desc">The Goldfish is the most commonly used domestic equatic fish. It was first domesticated in China more than a thousand years ago.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_shark">Shark</string>
    <string name="shark">Shark</string>
    <string name="shark_desc">The Sharks have five to seven gills slits on the side of the head. The smalles shark is about 17 centimeter and the biggest shark named white shark is the longest fish in the world.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sea_turtle">Sea Turtle</string>
    <string name="seaturtle">Sea Turtle</string>
    <string name="seaturtle_desc">The Sea Turtles are equatic reptiles. There are a total of seven species of Sea Turtles. Four of them have been identified as endangered.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_whale">Whale</string>
    <string name="whale">Whale</string>
    <string name="whale_desc">Whales are aquatic mammals. Their size ranges from 3.5m to 30m and weight from 150 lbs to 200 short tons or 180 long tons. Whales are long-lived, humpback whales living for up to 77 years, </string>
    <string name="title_activity_clown_fish">Clown Fish</string>
    <string name="clownfish">Clown Fish</string>
    <string name="clownfish_desc">the Clown Fish has thirty different species discovered so far. Clownfish are overall yellow, orange, or a reddish or blackish color, and many show white bars or patches. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_lobster">Lobster</string>
    <string name="lobster">Lobster</string>
    <string name="lobster_desc">The lobsters have long bodies with muscular tails, and live in crevices or burrows on the sea floor. Three of their five pairs of legs have claws, including the first pair, which are usually much larger than the others.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_crab">Crab</string>
    <string name="crab">Crab</string>
    <string name="crab_desc">They live in all the worlds oceans, in fresh water, and on land, are generally covered with a thick exoskeleton and have a single pair of claws.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_toad">Toad</string>
    <string name="toad">Toad</string>
    <string name="toad_desc">A toad is any of a number of species of amphibians in the order Anura (frogs) characterized by dry, leathery skin, short legs, and snout-like parotoid glands.</string>

</resources>
