<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">ChildFieldTrip</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_animal_title">AnimalTitle</string>
    <string name="title_activity_domestic">Domestic</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dog">Dog</string>
    <string name="title_activity_farm_animals">FarmAnimals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cat">Cat</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rodents">Rodents</string>
    <string name="title_activity_reptiles">Reptiles</string>
    <string name="title_activity_birds">Birds</string>
    <string name="title_activity_horse">Horse</string>

    <string-array name="farm">
        <item>Cow</item>
        <item>Horse</item>
        <item>Pig</item>
        <item>Sheep</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="amp">
        <item>Frog</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="freshlv">
        <item>Salmon</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="sealv">
        <item>Dolphin</item>
        <item>Octopus</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rep">
        <item>Corn Snake</item>
        <item>Turtle</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rod">
        <item>Guinea Pig</item>
        <item>Hamster</item>
        <item>Mouse</item>
        <item>Rabbit</item>
        <item>Rat</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="bird">
        <item>Parakeet</item>
        <item>Parrot</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildmamals">
        <item>Bear</item>
        <item>Deer</item>
        <item>Elephant</item>
        <item>Gazelle</item>
        <item>Giraffe</item>
        <item>Hippo</item>
        <item>Zebra</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildfelines">
        <item>Cheetah</item>
        <item>Lion</item>
        <item>Tiger</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildrodents">
        <item>Meerkat</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildreptiles">
        <item>Alligator</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildbirds">
        <item>Penguin</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wildcanines">
        <item>Wolf</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="pig">Pig</string>
    <string name="guineapig">Guinea Pig</string>
    <string name="hamster">Hamster</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cow">Cow</string>
    <string name="title_activity_parrot">Parrot</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rabbit">Rabbit</string>
    <string name="title_activity_turtle">Turtle</string>
    <string name="title_activity_camera">CameraActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mouse">Mouse</string>
    <string name="title_activity_rat">Rat</string>
    <string name="title_activity_parakeet">Parakeet</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sheep">Sheep</string>
    <string name="title_activity_corn_snake">CornSnake</string>
    <string name="go">Go</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to the Animal Field Guide!</string>
    <string name="animals">Animals</string>
    <string name="spellgame">Spell Game</string>
    <string name="wiki">Images and information taken from Wikipedia</string>
    <string name="exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="image">Image here</string>
    <string name="horse">Horse</string>
    <string name="dog">Dog</string>
    <string name="cat">Cat</string>
    <string name="mouse">Mouse</string>
    <string name="rat">Rat</string>
    <string name="rabbit">Rabbit</string>
    <string name="turtle">Turtle</string>
    <string name="cornsnake">Corn Snake</string>
    <string name="cow">Cow</string>
    <string name="sheep">Sheep</string>
    <string name="parakeet">Parakeet</string>
    <string name="parrot">Parrot</string>
    <string name="choose">Click to choose!</string>
    <string name="reptiles">Reptiles</string>
    <string name="rodents">Rodents</string>
    <string name="birds">Birds</string>
    <string name="canines">Canines</string>
    <string name="felines">Felines</string>
    <string name="farmanimals">Farm Animals</string>
    <string name="defaullt">Here we put the description for the dog. Like what the dog eats. Where the dog lives. What is interesting about the dog. Whatever else</string>
    <string name="search">Search for an animal</string>
    <string name="domestic">Domestic</string>
    <string name="aquatic">Aquatic</string>
    <string name="wild">Wild Animals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_tiger">Tiger</string>
    <string name="tiger">Tiger</string>
    <string name="tiger_desc">Its most recognizable feature is a pattern of dark vertical stripes on reddish-orange fur with a lighter underside. The tiger (Panthera tigris) is the largest cat species, reaching a total body length of up to 3.3 m (11 ft) and weighing up to 306 kg (675 lb).</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cheetah">Cheetah</string>
    <string name="cheetah">Cheetah</string>
    <string name="cheetah_desc">The cheetah is a large feline inhabiting most of Africa and parts of the Middle East. The cheetah can run faster than any other land animal, as fast as 70 to 75 mph, and has the ability to accelerate from 0 to 62 mph in three seconds.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lion">Lion</string>
    <string name="lion">Lion</string>
    <string name="lion_desc">The lion is one of the four big cats in the genus Panthera and a member of the family Felidae. With some males exceeding 250 kg (550 lb) in weight. it is the second-largest living cat after the tiger.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_zebra">Zebra</string>
    <string name="zebra">Zebra</string>
    <string name="zebra_desc">Zebras are several species of African equids (horse family) united by their distinctive black and white stripes. Their stripes come in different patterns, unique to each individual.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_deer">Deer</string>
    <string name="deer">Deer</string>
    <string name="deer_desc">Deer (singular and plural) are the ruminant mammals that comprise the family Cervidae. Species therein include white-tailed deer, such mule deer as black-tailed deer, elk, moose, red deer, reindeer fallow deer, roe deer, pudú and chital.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_giraffe">Giraffe</string>
    <string name="giraffe">Giraffe</string>
    <string name="giraffe_desc">The giraffe (Giraffa camelopardalis) is an African even-toed ungulate mammal, the tallest living terrestrial animal and the largest ruminant. Its species name refers to its camel-like appearance and the patches of color on its fur.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bear">Bear</string>
    <string name="bear">Bear</string>
    <string name="bear_desc">Bears are mammals of the family Ursidae. They are caniforms, or doglike carnivorans, with the pinnipeds being their closest living relatives. Although only eight species of bears are extant, they are widespread.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gazelle">Gazelle</string>
    <string name="gazelle">Gazelle</string>
    <string name="gazelle_desc">A gazelle is any of many antelope species in the genus Gazella, or formerly considered to belong to it. Six species are included in two genera, Eudorcas and Nanger, which were formerly considered subgenera</string>
    <string name="title_activity_elephant">Elephant</string>
    <string name="elephant">Elephant</string>
    <string name="elephant_desc">Elephants are large mammals of the family Elephantidae and the order Proboscidea. Traditionally, two species are recognised, the African elephant (Loxodonta africana) and the Asian elephant (Elephas maximus).</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hippo">Hippo</string>
    <string name="hippo">Hippo</string>
    <string name="hippo_desc">Hippos are recognizable by their barrel-shaped torsos, enormous mouths and teeth, nearly hairless bodies, stubby legs and tremendous size. They are the third-largest type of land mammal by weight (between 1½ and 3 tonnes).</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_animals">WildAnimals</string>
    <string name="mammalso">Other Mammals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_other_mammals">OtherMammals</string>
    <string name="title_activity_canines">Canines</string>
    <string name="title_activity_felines">Felines</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_rodents">WildRodents</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_reptiles">WildReptiles</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wild_birds">WildBirds</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hamster">Hamster</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pig">Pig</string>
    <string name="title_activity_guineapig">Guineapig</string>
    <string name="title_activity_alligator">Alligator</string>
    <string name="alligator">Alligator</string>
    <string name="alligator_desc">An alligator is a crocodilian in the genus Alligator of the family Alligatoridae. The two living species are the American alligator (A. mississippiensis) and the Chinese alligator (A. sinensis).</string>
    <string name="title_activity_meerkat">Meerkat</string>
    <string name="meerkat">Meerkat</string>
    <string name="meerkat_desc">The meerkat or suricate, Suricata suricatta, is a small mammal belonging to the mongoose family. Meerkats live in all parts of the Kalahari Desert in Botswana, in much of the Namib Desert in Namibia and southwestern Angola,</string>
    <string name="title_activity_penguin">Penguin</string>
    <string name="penguin">Penguin</string>
    <string name="penguin_desc">Penguins (order Sphenisciformes, family Spheniscidae) are a group of aquatic, flightless birds living almost exclusively in the Southern Hemisphere, especially in Antarctica.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wolf">Wolf</string>
    <string name="wolf">Wolf</string>
    <string name="wolf_desc">The gray wolf or grey wolf (Canis lupus) is a canid native to the wilderness and remote areas of North America, Eurasia, and North Africa. It is the largest member of its family, with males averaging 43–45 kg (95–99 lb),</string>
    <string name="deerinfo">Deer is both singular and plural way to refer to deers. They are also mmals and come from the Cervidae family. The males have antlers. They live in tundras to tropical forests. They are also herbivores.</string>
    <string name="facts">Facts</string>
    <string name="definitions">Definitions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_database_manager">DatabaseManager</string>
    <string name="catinfo">Cats are carniorous mammals. They are kept as indoor pets. They are valued by people for hunting vermin and being companions. They have quick reflexes, sharp claws, and are flexible.</string>
    <string name="cornsnakeinfo">Corn snakes are a popular breed of snake to keep as pets. They are carnivorous and eat  small rodents. Sometimes they may even eat smaller reptiles or unguarded bird eggs in the wild. They are found in the southeastern and central United States. </string>
    <string name="cowinfo">Cow are also called cattle. They are raised to be dairy animals for milk, or livestock for meat,. They were domesticated from southeast Turkey and there are about 1.3 billion of them in the world today.</string>
    <string name="doginfo">They are mammals part of the Canidae family and are subspecies of gray wolves. They were the first animal to be domesticated. They arenow used mostly as pets but were formally mostly domesticated for safety.</string>
    <string name="guineainfo">They are not in the pig family, but are actually rodents. They came from Andes. These animals are pets that were introduced by European traders to WEstern societies.  They eat vegitation. </string>
    <string name="hamsterinfo">Hamsters are mostly active during the night so they can avoid predators. Their diets may consist of seeds, vegetation, fruits and sometimes even insects. Their cheek pouches reach their shoulders so they can carry food to their homes. </string>
    <string name="horseinfo"> Horses are one of two subspecies of equus ferus. They are mammals that have evolved from around 50 million ears from being small multi-toed creatures into what they are today. They were domesticated around 4000 BC. They are used in many human activities such as police work, sports, agriculture, and riding. They are herbivores. </string>
    <string name="mouseinfo">Mice are small mammals. They are largely herbivores that eat grains. They are nocturnal animals. As well as being popular pets they are used as test subjects in labatories.</string>
    <string name="parakeetinfo">They are a subspecies of parrot. The ringnecked parakeet is the type native to Africa and Asia. This species is popular as a pet. </string>
    <string name="parrotinfo">Parrots are found in tropical and subtropical regions. They are divided into three superfamilies: true parrots, New Zealand parrots, and cockatoos.  South America and Australasia have the greatest diversity of parrots. Their diets consists of seeds, fruit, nuts, buds, and other parts of plants. A few eat animals.</string>
    <string name="piginfo">Pigs ancestors are the common Eurasian wild boar. Baby pigs are called piglets. They are omnivores and like to be social.  They are commonly raised on farms for pork, ham, and even leather. </string>
    <string name="rabbitinfo">Rabbits are mammals and found in many places over the world. A male rabbit is refered to as a buck while the female as a doe. However a baby rabbit is called a kitten.  They live in meadows, woods, deserts, and grasslands. They are most active dawn and dusk and are herbivores. </string>
    <string name="ratinfo">Rats are often considered pests. However they have an ability to learn and are often kept as pets. They are often used in labatories.</string>
    <string name="sheepinfo">They are licestock mammals. They likely descended from mouflon in Europe and Asia. They are raised for meat, milk, and fleece. Their wool is the most used animal fiber.</string>
    <string name="turtleinfo">Turtles have a bony(cartilaginous) shell that is formed from their ribs. This shell acts like a protective sheild. They are amniotes, which means they breathe air, and do not go underwater to lay eggs, but live around water.  They feed on aquatic plants and sometimes insects. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_spell_game">SpellGame</string>
    <string name="title_activity_image_guess">ImageGuess</string>
    <string name="title_activity_guess_image">GuessImage</string>
    <string name="title_activity_frog">Frog</string>
    <string name="frog">Frog</string>
    <string name="froginfo">Frogs are short-bodied and tailless. They evolve from a stage called tadpole. When they are tadpoles they are mostly herbivors but once they evolve they are carnivores. They used their cleft tongue to catch flies.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_aquatic">Aquatic</string>
    <string name="fresh">Fresh Water</string>
    <string name="amphibian">Amphibian</string>
    <string name="sea">Sea Water</string>
    <string name="title_activity_amphibian">Amphibian</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fresh_water">FreshWater</string>
    <string name="title_activity_salmon">Salmon</string>
    <string name="salmon">Salmon</string>
    <string name="dolphin">Dolphin</string>
    <string name="salmoninfo">Salmon are born  anadromous, which means they are born in the water. They then migrate to the ocean and only return  to fresh water to reproduce.  </string>
    <string name="title_activity_sea_water">SeaWater</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dolphin">Dolphin</string>
    <string name="dolphininfo">Dolphins are mammals that are closely related to whales. They eat squid and fish. They are thought of as most intelligent animal and are highly social.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_octopus">Octopus</string>
    <string name="octopus">Octopus</string>
    <string name="octopusinfo">Octupus have eight arms. Their mouthes have a hard beak and are located in the center of their arms. To defend themselves they will spray ink at their predators.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_monkey">Monkey</string>
    <string name="monkey">Monkey</string>
    <string name="monkey_desc">A monkey is any nonhuman primate, with the usual exception of the lemurs and tarsiers.[1] Thus defined, there are three type of monkeys: (1) non-human hominoids (also known as apes), (2) old world monkeys, and (3) new world monkeys.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gorilla">Gorilla</string>
    <string name="gorilla">Gorilla</string>
    <string name="gorilla_desc">Gorillas constitute the eponymous genus Gorilla, the largest extant genus of primates by physical size. They are ground-dwelling, predominantly herbivorous apes that inhabit the forests of central Africa. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_baboon">Baboon</string>
    <string name="baboon">Baboon</string>
    <string name="baboon_desc">Baboons are African and Arabian Old World monkeys belonging to the genus Papio, part of the subfamily Cercopithecinae. The five species are some of the largest non-hominoid members of the primate order; only the mandrill and the drill are larger.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_buffalo">Buffalo</string>
    <string name="buffalo">Buffalo</string>
    <string name="buffalo_desc">The water buffalo or domestic Asian water buffalo (Bubalus bubalis) is a large bovid found on the Indian subcontinent to Vietnam and Peninsular Malaysia, in Sri Lanka, in Luzon Island in the Philippines, and in Borneo.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_boar">Boar</string>
    <string name="boar">Boar</string>
    <string name="boar_desc">Wild boar or wild pig (Sus scrofa) is a species of the pig genus Sus, part of the biological family Suidae. The species includes many subspecies. It is the wild ancestor of the domestic pig, an animal with which it freely hybridises</string>
    

</resources>
